[
  {
    "question": "One way to evaluate whether a decision aligns with honesty and integrity is to use the _______ test.<br />&nbsp;(1)  headline<br />&nbsp;(2) guilt",
    "answer": "One way to evaluate whether a decision aligns with honesty and integrity is to use the headline test."
  },
  {
    "question": "Duties to clients are derived from two key sources: ________ and _________.",
    "answer": "Duties to clients are derived from two key sources: common law and legislation."
  },
  {
    "question": "A person who holds a position of trust with respect to someone else and is obliged, by virtue of that relationship, to act solely for the other person’s benefit is a ___________.",
    "answer": "A person who holds a position of trust with respect to someone else and is obliged, by virtue of that relationship, to act solely for the other person’s benefit is a fiduciary."
  },
  {
    "question": "A licensee’s duty of confidentiality to a client:<br />&nbsp;(1) ends when the relationship between the licensee and client ends.<br />&nbsp;(2) lasts forever.",
    "answer": "A licensee’s duty of confidentiality to a client:<br />&nbsp;(1) ends when the relationship between the licensee and client ends.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) lasts forever.</strong>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Licensees are required to disclose to their clients all known ________ _________ regarding real estate services.",
    "answer": "Licensees are required to disclose to their clients all known material information regarding real estate services."
  },
  {
    "question": "When a conflict of interest arises, it must be:<br />&nbsp;(1) evidence of wrongdoing.<br />&nbsp;(2) handled promptly and appropriately.",
    "answer": "When a conflict of interest arises, it must be:<br />&nbsp;(1) evidence of wrongdoing.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) handled promptly and appropriately.</strong>"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to meet their professional standards, licensees only need to act in accordance with the Real Estate Services Act.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "In order to meet their professional standards, licensees only need to act in accordance with the Real Estate Services Act.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />Compliance with the Real Estate Services Act may not be enough to satisfy one’s professional obligations.  Licensees must also observe ethical duties as part of meeting their professional obligations."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a licensee discovers the misconduct of a colleague at their brokerage, they:<br />&nbsp;(1) must report it to their managing broker.<br />&nbsp;(2) should try to deal with the misconduct internally.",
    "answer": "If a licensee discovers the misconduct of a colleague at their brokerage, they:<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) must report it to their managing broker.</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) should try to deal with the misconduct internally."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a real estate professional discovers the misconduct of a licensee at a different brokerage, they:<br />&nbsp;(1)   must report it to their managing broker.<br />&nbsp;(2)   have no explicit duty in the Real Estate Services Rules to report the misconduct, but should talk to their managing broker anyway.",
    "answer": "If a real estate professional discovers the misconduct of a licensee at a different brokerage, they:<br />&nbsp;(1) must report it to their managing broker.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) have no explicit duty in the Real Estate Services Rules to report the misconduct, but should talk to their managing broker anyway.</strong><br />While there is no explicit duty in the Rules for licensees to report the misconduct of those outside their brokerage, licensees do have a professional duty to report this conduct."
  },
  {
    "question": "The only code of ethics for real estate licensees are the duties contained in the <em>Real Estate Services Rules.</em><br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "The only code of ethics for real estate licensees are the duties contained in the <em>Real Estate Services Rules.</em><br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />Professional real estate associations often have their own codes of ethics, which their members are obligated to follow."
  },
  {
    "question": "When a conflict of interest arises, a licensee must:<br />&nbsp;(1) promptly and fully disclose the conflict to their client.<br />&nbsp;(2) immediately sever all ties with their client.",
    "answer": "When a conflict of interest arises, a licensee must:<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) promptly and fully disclose the conflict to their client.</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) immediately sever all ties with their client."
  },
  {
    "question": "Licensees should try to answer all of their client’s questions, even if they are in doubt as to whether they have the required expertise.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Licensees should try to answer all of their client’s questions, even if they are in doubt as to whether they have the required expertise.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />Licensees should refer a client to a competent professional if they have doubts as to whether they have the required expertise to answer a particular question."
  },
  {
    "question": "Licensees can provide their opinion and advice on how their client should respond to a given offer, provided that it is objective.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Licensees can provide their opinion and advice on how their client should respond to a given offer, provided that it is objective.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False<br />Licensees providing an opinion or advice on how to respond to a given offer must be objective and cannot be influenced by inappropriate considerations like personal interest or bias."
  },
  {
    "question": "One exception to the duty to communicate all offers to a client in a timely way is when:<br />&nbsp;(1) the client specifically instructs their licensee not to communicate offers to them promptly.<br />&nbsp;(2) a licensee knows the client will decline an offer.",
    "answer": "One exception to the duty to communicate all offers to a client in a timely way is when:<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) the client specifically instructs their licensee not to communicate offers to them promptly.</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) a licensee knows the client will decline an offer."
  },
  {
    "question": "A licensee’s failure to meet their obligations as a trusted professional is generally seen as a breach of _______ ________.",
    "answer": "A licensee’s failure to meet their obligations as a trusted professional is generally seen as a breach of professional ethics."
  },
  {
    "question": "Acting contrary to the best interests of the public is an example of ________ _______.",
    "answer": "Acting contrary to the best interests of the public is an example of conduct unbecoming."
  },
  {
    "question": "If a client does not seem to understand or appreciate a disclosure by the licensee, the licensee should:<br />&nbsp;(1) have a further conversation with the client to ensure they understand.<br />&nbsp;(2) decide whether that information is really relevant to the client or not.",
    "answer": "If a client does not seem to understand or appreciate a disclosure by the licensee, the licensee should:<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) have a further conversation with the client to ensure they understand.</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) decide whether that information is really relevant to the client or not."
  },
  {
    "question": "A licensee can sign an agreement for a client if the client verbally authorizes it.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "A licensee can sign an agreement for a client if the client verbally authorizes it.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />Section 45 of the Real Estate Services Rules requires licensees to obtain written authorization to sign agreements on behalf of their clients."
  },
  {
    "question": "The safest practice for disclosures is to ensure that they are made (or provided) in _________.",
    "answer": "The safest practice for disclosures is to ensure that they are in writing."
  }
]